6205 N Oakland Ave, Indianapolis IN, 46220

🛚 (+1) (734)604-6163 | 💌 andrew.lyjak@gmail.com | 🏕 spacelyjak.rtfd.io | 🖸 alyjak | 🛅 andrew-lyjak | 💆 @spacelyjak

Company Recruitment Team

September 25, 2018

CLEAROBJECT 8627 EAST 116TH STREET, SUITE 300 FISHERS, IN 46038

Job Application for Software Test Engineer or Full Stack Developer

To whom it may concern,

About Me_

I recently moved with my wife to the Indianapolis area after working for SpaceX in Los Angeles for eight years. I am currently working remotely for SpaceX, but I am looking for new adventures in an exciting, technology driven company.

My interests revolve around bridging the digital and physical world in ways that are intuitive and safe. At SpaceX, I implement and execute software assurance activities related to ensuring the safety and quality of flight software for the F9 and Dragon vehicles. In this position I have gathered and maintained experience in a diverse range of engineering fields: examples include the "hard" engineering fields such as aerospace, electrical, and computer engineering, as well as the "soft" engineering fields such as process, quality, and requirements engineering.

Why ClearObject? _____

Internet of Things interest me greatly – because of both its promise as well as its pitfalls. IOT promises to provide new capabilities and connectivity to consumers and businesses, its pitfalls are avoidable, and mainly revolve around the problems an insecurely connected world entails. I am looking for exiting opportunities at the forefront of this burgeoning industry in Indianapolis. I find ClearObject particularly exciting because of the respect you have in the local community, the strength of your services, and your focus on the platforms underlying IOT progress.

Why Me? _____

I believe my diverse range of skills is ideal for your Software Test Engineer position. In addition, my skills make me a promising candidate for your full stack developer position. Through SpaceX, I have experience in each role and responsibility identified within the Software Test Engineer job posting. Although I have an Aerospace degree, I have worked in Computer Engineering/Science fields both within college and through my eight years at SpaceX. I have demonstrated my ability to learn new material quickly and efficiently and I am known to be self-driven and to enjoy solving challenging problems. I pride myself in basing my work on principles, this helps maintain focus on the right solution, not just what is currently popular or hyped. I believe I have established a reputation for being reliable and a valued and respected member of each team I have had the pleasure of working with.

Sincerely,

Andrew W. Lyjak



SOFTWARE ASSURANCE/VERIFICATION/DEVELOPMENT · SYSTEMS ENG

6205 N Oakland Ave, Indianapolis IN, 46220

□ (+1) (734)604-6163 | ■ andrew.lyjak@gmail.com | 🌴 spacelyjak.rtfd.io | 🖫 alyjak | 🛅 andrew-lyjak | 💆 @spacelyjak

"This is the real secret of life – to be completely engaged with what you are doing in the here and now. And instead of calling it work, realize it is play."

Education

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, Michigan

M.E. IN SPACE SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

2009 - 2010

GPA: 3.769/4.000

University of Michigan
B.E. Aerospace Engineering

Ann Arbor, Michigan

2005 - 2009

Minor in German

• GPA: 3.456/4.000

Skills_

Programming Python, LTFX, ReStructuredText, Bash, Linux, R, Rust, C, C++

Web Django with Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Systems Engineering Regulation and Certification, Verification Planning, Fault Tolerance Analysis, Risk and Change Management

Software Quality git, Trac, Subversion, JIRA, Software Development Planning, Quality Audits

Languages English, German

Experience _____

Software Mission Assurance Engineer

Hawthorne, CA

SPACEX 2010 - Present

SOFTWARE CERTIFICATION FOR NASA SAFETY AND QUALITY REQUIREMENTS

2010 - Present

- Wrote the Flight Software Development Plan. This document defines SpaceX's custom agile development process for designing, developing, and verifying flight software.
- Designed, wrote, and maintain the Cargo Dragon Flight Software "Computer Based Control Systems" documentation. This material is used to demonstrate compliance with NASA software safety requirements and also defines many of the software safety test and analysis activities executed for verification of software safety related to the Dragon cargo vehicle.
- Perform process audits to verify software quality, and compliance with NASA requirements for the Dragon cargo vehicle.
- Maintain audits, and safety documents through all changes to system design and software for each new commercial cargo resupply mission

Independent Verification and Validation (IVV) Contract Management

2010 - Present

- Serve as the technical point of contact for SpaceX's IVV Contracts for safety critical software.
- Provide the contractor with sufficient data to effectively evaluate the safety of the flight software. Contractor evaluates system design, source code, and verification results.
- Ensure the contractor's feedback is internally addressed and incorporated to create a better product for each commercial crew and cargo
- Manage contracts associated with IVV of flight software for Crew Dragon, Cargo Dragon, and the Autonomous Flight Termination System.

SOFTWARE PROCESS TOOL DEVELOPMENT

- 2012 Present
- **branchdiff** Developed an application to view the differences between two Subversion branches to facilitate merge decisions between them. Displays differences as commits or as the set tickets referenced within those commit messages.
- Developed an application for viewing change over time for various Trac ticket queries.
- Performed trade studies on various software development ticketing systems. The study factored into SpaceX's decision to adopt JIRA across multiple business domains.
- ReadTheManual Installed, modified, and adminstered an internal fork of ReadTheDocs for use within the SpaceX intranet. This service is used to build and distribute documentation for over 160 internal projects.
- **Tracegraph** Designed and developed a library for defining systems relationships across information housed within multiple data silos. The library is used for verification tracking purposes to support compliance tracking of SpaceX processes to customer requirements.

DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE SPACEX SOFTWARE STANDARD

2013 - Prese

• Developed a software engineering standard for SpaceX. The standard provides a set of requirements to be applied to different classifications of software development, classifications include A, for safety and mission critical software, through D, used for desktop, R&D, or other non-critical applications. The standard is used to evaluate the quality of all softare processes related to the Commercial Crew system.

FAULT TOLERANCE ANALYSIS 2016 - Present

- Co-developed the **Fault Tolerance Analyis Process**. This process is used to evaluate autonomous and/or operator controlled electrome-chanical systems. Analysis is used to assess the fault tolerance of a design in order to determine its capabilities and develop fault detection, isolation, and recovery logic for managing redundant capabilities.
- Developed test and analysis plans for verifying fault tolerance as defined through the Fault Tolerance Analysis products.
- With a team of 6 other engineers, executed the Fault Tolerance Analysis Process against 25 separate autonomous control systems within the Crew Dragon Architecture over the course of a year.